econocom.com 2009-06-29

# Privacy Statement | Econocom

### Preamble

This Confidentiality Charter applies to the official website of the Econocom Group ([www.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/)), the editor of which is Econocom, and not necessarily to other websites of the Econocom Group.  
You should read the Confidentiality Charter applicable to this website. By accessing this website and using it, you accept the provisions of this Confidentiality Charter. Not accepting the provisions of this Charter will prevent you from accessing the services provided on this website.  
The name Econocom cited in this charter means the Econocom company, its parent company Econocom Group SA/NV, its direct or indirect subsidiaries, and/or its service providers which contribute or have contributed to the creation of this Internet website.

### Data collected

**Non-personal information collected automatically**  
Econocom undertakes to maintain the confidential nature of the identity of visitors to its website. Econocom can provide overall statistics concerning visitors to the site, data analyzing their profile and other information to third parties related to the website. These statistics under no circumstances contain information enabling the identification of any person.

**The collection of personal information**  
In order to be able to reply to your questions or your requests and to manage the public interaction systems, Econocom may request from you, either on an optional or an obligatory basis, personal information such as your name, address, e-mail address and telephone numbers, etc. This information will be faithfully and lawfully obtained and processed. It will be recorded for defined and legitimate purposes and will be used in compliance with those purposes. It will be the subject of precautions that will ensure the security of the data in order to prevent the data from becoming damaged, modified, destroyed or communicated to non-authorized third parties.

If the Internet user does not provide the obligatory information, the form cannot be validated and its information will not be retained.

**Purpose of collection**  
The purpose of collection is to enable:

  * Econocom to answer your questions, to contact you by letter, e-mail or telephone so that you can be informed of news about the group or its website,
  * Econocom to carry out investigations and surveys, if necessary. The Internet user is then advised of the specific use of the information collected.
  * the Internet user to access the interactive areas in this [www.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/ "www.econocom.com") Econocom Group website.

**Collection addressee(s)**  
If you order a publication, request a service or submit content to this website, Econocom may need to contact you to obtain additional information required for the processing of your request.  
However, Econocom will not provide this information to a third party without your authorization, unless legally obliged to do so or unless required to do so in order to process your request or for the management of public interaction systems.

You also give Econocom the right to share all communicated information with its suppliers or associated companies for the processing stated above. In such case, the said suppliers or associated companies will be notified of the rectifications and/or cancellations of personal information.

**Period for which personal information will be kept**  
The personal data and/or information relating to the Internet user's navigation on our website will not be kept for a period that is longer than necessary for the purposes of the relevant processing and that is within the maximum period of 5 years.

**Security**  
The act of providing personal data (whether directly on the website, by telephone or by Internet) is never without risk, and the electronic communication systems cannot be totally protected against "sabotage" or "pirating". However, Econocom undertakes reasonable measures aimed at anticipating and maintaining the integrity of the data and reducing the risks so that any access by non-authorized third parties to your personal information and any abusive or incorrect use of it is prevented.

Econocom endeavors to provide full and correct information on the services offered in this website. However, it is possible that errors may not be picked up by the webmaster. Econocom cannot be held liable for any eventual error contained in this website, whether or not it is likely to cause damage. On the other hand, those errors will, where possible, be rapidly corrected by Econocom when so requested.

### Data protection

Whether on its own initiative or as requested by you, Econocom can complete, modify or delete  incomplete, incorrect or out-of-date personal data that is retained for and relates to the operation of this website.  
You can, by simple request to the site webmaster ([webmaster.be@econocom.be](mailto:webmaster.be@econocom.be)), have access to your data and request its modification or deletion.  
Any member of the interactive area of the website [www.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/) benefits from a right of rectification that enables him to request at any time the deletion of his contributions by contacting the service in charge of access rights. Because of technical restrictions, Internet users must make their requests for deletion within a maximum period of one (1) month from the date of first publication of the message on the website w[ww.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/).

### Visitor identification

Other than the personal information that you may provide, this website can use technologies that enable certain technical information to be obtained such as your IP address, your computer's operating system, which Internet navigator you use, the methods of transferring data, etc.

The website [www.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/) may use cookies enabling the recording of information relating to your computer's navigation on our website (pages consulted, date and time of connection.)  
A cookie does not enable you to be personally identified.

The collection of this type of information will enable Econocom to improve the website so that it meets users' demands.

If you do not want to receive cookies or you would like to be notified that they are being used, you can specify this in your Internet navigator, as follows:

  * If you use Internet Explorer 3 or 4 (Microsoft) navigator: click "display", "option", "advanced". Among the different warnings that you can activate, the fourth is entitled "warn before accepting cookies and, solely for Internet Explorer 4, the fifth is entitled "always refuse cookies.
  * If you use a Navigator Gold 3 (Netscape) navigator: click "options", "network preferences", "protocols". Among the different warnings that you can activate, the first is entitled "warn before accepting a cookie". You will then be warned when a cookie arrives and you can block it being recorded.

### Minors

No information can be provided to Econocom by persons who are under 18 years of age without prior consent from a parent or a legal representative.

### Modifications

Econocom reserves the right to modify this Confidentiality Charter and to modify or prevent access to this website; Econocom can also modify its content at any time with or without notice.

### Copyrights

**Econocom Corporate Values**  
JL DERU Viaduc de Millau, architecte : Sir Norman Foster, maître de l'ouvrage : Compagnie Eiffage du Viaduc de Millau, études tablier et lançage : bureau Greisch ; CORBIS UK LTD / Jupiterimages ; Riser, UpperCut Images, Photodisc / Gettyimages

© 2009 – website [www.econocom.com](http://www.econocom.com/ "www.econocom.com"). All rights reserved - [Legal notices ](http://www.econocom.com/econocom-legal-information)
